# Shayaan Iqbal

Extremely efficient Unity Developer and game designer with extensive experience of 3.5 years in gaming industry. I am seeking a position in which my creative skills programming, game project management and Industry knowledge can be used as an asset to the company.

Address: A3 block, Johar, Town, Lahore, Pakistan



+923017689696



M Gmail

shayaan.dev@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Sr. Software Engineer- Unity Developer (C#) — GenITeam Solutions, Lahore

Jan 2024 - Present

Working currently as gameplay programmer & Multiplayer Programmer. My main roles are:

- Team management and planning about product release and development. Training of new resources
- Game economy design
- Multiplayer development and Chara

# Software Engineer- Unity Developer (C#) — GenITeam **Solutions**. Lahore

June 2022 - Dec 2023

Working currently as gameplay programmer. My main roles are

- Providing feasible and optimized code structures for the game
- Project planning & Design Discussion with Game Designers
- Game economy design
- Character controllers with any modifications
- ❖ Game performance optimizations and direction to art team for optimized assets
- Editor scripting
- Characters AI Implementations
- Documentation and process setup for new tools and technologies in
- R & D about new tools implementation
- Technical support and collaboration with team for any project related issues
- Troubleshooting

# Associate Software Engineer- Unity Developer (C#) — GenITeam **Solutions**, Lahore

July 2021 - June 2022

Worked as a Gameplay programmer with Unity. My main roles were to.

#### **SKILLS**

- Gameflow Design
- Storyboarding & Plot
- Game Mechanics
- Level Design
- **♦** C#
- ♦ C++
- ❖ 00P
- Unity 3D
- ❖ Asset Bundles
- Addressable Assets
- Game Programming Patterns
- SOLID Principles
- Unity Editor Scripting for Feasibility
- AI For Games
- Character Controllers
- Vector Math for Game Development
- Unity Physics Engine for Game Development
- Unity Animation System/State Machine Behaviors
- Character IK Programming
- Particles System Modules with Scripting
- Memory Management & Optimization / Profiler
- Unity Lightning Techniques for Optimized Lightning Implementation
- Leaderboards / Login Authentication Firebase
- Friends System in Online Games

Worked on Action Third person, First person & Simulation games

- Creating Character Controllers
- AI of different Types for enemy
- Base project Development of different Categories
- Implementing game design principles for good user Experience.
- Scalable and optimized project structure setup
- IK Programming and management for characters
- Creating Combat systems for Games
- Physics system for complex controllers
- ❖ Animations management along with character in game
- Cut Scene Creation and VFX & SFX Implementation with Sequencing window
- Performance Analysis with profiler and implementing feasible solutions
- Ads and in App implementations

# *Unity Developer (C#)*— **Mach Square Games,** Lahore

Feb 2021 - July 2021

Started my full-time game developer job in industry as a Unity Programmer. My main roles were to.

- \* To create Games for Mobile Android and IOS
- Working on Simulation, Action, Racing, 2D Games
- Code Architecture and refactoring
- My roles were to resolve release problems and bugs

- Git
- Mobile Games Android/IOS
- Game Cloud Data Management for online Games
- ❖ Game Design
- Level Design Economy Design
- Team Management
- Project Planning
- Project Management
- Economy Design
- Multi-Platform Builds (Android, IOS, Amazon, Huawei)
- Project Management
- New Tools and Technology Implementations
- Photoshop

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Information Technology University,** Lahore— *BSComputer Science*

September 2017 - June 2021

**LANGUAGES** 

**Punjab Group of Colleges,** Okara — *Intermediate* 

Urdu

English

Year 2017

**Falcon Public School,** Okara— *Matric* 

Year 2015

#### **PROJECTS**

Some of my main projects are mentioned below:

# Play Time Adventure:

 $\underline{https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.zatg.scaryteacher.campescape\&hl=en\&gl=US\&pli=1$ 

# Hide and prank:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.zatg.catchme.pranks

#### Cat simulator:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.genigames.straycat.survival&hl=en

### Baby in diaper:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.gtl.littlebigimposter

#### Tiny toon guys:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.genigames.tiny.toons.guys

#### Meme shooter:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sniper.shooting.fps.battle

#### Cheat and run:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.zakg.scaryteacher.cheat.games

### **Scary Robber:**

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.zatg.scaryrobber.boylife

# Nick and Tani:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.zatg.nick.tani.lovepuzzle